# **GRANT CAWLEY**

Raleigh, NC 27613

Phone: (636) 368-7221 • Email: grantlcawley@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/grant-cawley-89249415b/

GitHub: https://github.com/cawlevgl • Portfolio: https://cawlev-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

## **SUMMARY**

Full-stack web developer utilizing background in psychology to create dynamic new experiences and continue pursuit of learning. Prioritizes thinking from the perspective of the user to create new user functionality in online spaces. Dedicated problem-solver known for being a team player.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Tools and Technologies:** Github, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, jQuery, Node.js, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Bootstrap, MUI, REST APIs, Hasura, GraphQL, Netlify AWS Lambda Functions, Responsive Design, Progressive Web Applications (PWAs), Local Storage, Visual Studio Code, Chrome DevTools **Languages:** English, Conversational Spanish

## **PROJECTS**

Blackjack Casino & Multiplayer Blackjack Casino https://github.com/EgiVilza/Casino Multiplayer https://casino-multiplayer.herokuapp.com/https://github.com/EgiVilza/Project2 https://frozen-wildwood-18963.herokuapp.com

- Summary: A web application that allows the user to play Blackjack and save their score to a
  database. The updated multiplayer version allows users to sign up and play with others online
  using WebSockets.
- Role: Front-End and Back-End Developer
- Tools: React, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, Socket.io, MongoDB, Mongoose

**Nutritious Recipe Generator** • <a href="https://github.com/EgiVilza/NutritiousRecipeGenerator">https://egivilza.github.io/NutritiousRecipeGenerator</a>

- Summary: A web application that displays recipes from different recipe API's for easy viewing and saving. It allows the user to select dietary restrictions and region of origin.
- Role: Front-End and Back-End Developer
- Tools: HTML, Javascript, CSS, Materialize, Positionstack API, Edamam Recipe API, TheMealDB API

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Junior Frontend Developer**

Hopdrive - Richmond, VA

Worked independently and as a member of a team, utilizing web development languages and technologies to improve and maintain applications that aided in transporting vehicles for companies in the automotive industry.

Key Accomplishments:

 Gained valuable professional experience with Github, Javascript, React, MUI, Node.js, REST APIs, Netlify AWS Lambda Functions, Hasura, GraphQL and other technologies.

### **Tutor Engagement Specialist**

2019 - 2020

2021 - Present

Varsity Tutors - Saint Louis, MO

Utilized communication, problem-solving and critical thinking to negotiate logistical details, including pay rates and location, with tutors and their prospective students. *Key Accomplishments:* 

• Fulfilled administrative and training duties along with Tutor Engagement role.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Certificate in Full Stack Web Development**

2020 - 2021

Washington University, St. Louis, MO

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js, & React.

## **Bachelor of Science in Psychology and Spanish**

2014 - 2018